{
    "id": "26310db7c83f486ca591a8e9269929fe",
    "title": "Degrees Of Comparison Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "She is senior ................................... me by five years.",
            "description": "The adjectives senior and junior are followed by the preposition to.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "of",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "My job is superior ..................................... yours.",
            "description": "The adjectives superior and inferior are followed by the preposition to.",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "of",
                "to"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "James is ........................................  his brother.",
            "description": "We use the comparative to compare one person or thing with another person or thing.",
            "answers": [
                "tallest of",
                "taller than",
                "taller then"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She sings ......................................... as her sister.",
            "description": "We use constructions with as...as... to say that two persons or things are similar.",
            "answers": [
                "as best",
                "as well",
                "better"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I earn as ..................................... money as you do.",
            "description": "Adjectives or adverbs of the positive degree are used in this construction.",
            "answers": [
                "much",
                "more",
                "much more"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Samuel is ........................................ of the four boys.",
            "description": "We use the superlative to compare one or thing with the group to which that person or thing also belongs.",
            "answers": [
                "taller than",
                "tallest than",
                "the tallest"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am quite …………………………….. with what I have achieved.",
            "description": "We use the positive adjective when there is no idea of comparison.",
            "answers": [
                "happy",
                "happier",
                "happiest"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is …………………………… difficult problem I have ever encountered.",
            "description": "We make the superlative form of difficult with most. The article the is used before superlative adjectives.",
            "answers": [
                "the more",
                "the most",
                "most"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are …………………………… woman I have ever met.",
            "description": "The superlative form of kind is kindest.",
            "answers": [
                "the kindest",
                "the most kind",
                "the most kindest"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is as interesting …………………………. that.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "than",
                "as",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I am …………………………….. in movies than concerts.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "most interested",
                "more interested",
                "as interested"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You are no ............................................. him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "better of",
                "better than",
                "best of"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}